Cleveland Hall of Fame for including me
with a lot of wonderful people over the
years. Um, as Jack Fenny said one time
when he was being honored, you know, I
don't really deserve this honor, but
then again, I've got arthritis and I
don't deserve that either.
I was particularly touched that Sanji
was my presenter. He um his own advice
is hyperbole which
you but he is one of my favorite alltime
lawyers that I've worked with. He's a
he's a magnificent lawyer. He uh uh
right now he's commuting between here
and Salo to help us open an office in
Brazil. He uh does it without any
complaint. And uh I know
that one example of how truly
outstanding he is. It was back in
2002 and there's a European magazine
called merger markets and they ranked
the top five lawyers on European deals
in that year. Here's Sanjie Kapoor in
the top five lawyers and on European
deals out of Cleveland, Ohio.
[Applause]
So, thank you very much, Eli. That was
just above and beyond. I deeply
appreciate it. I'm glad you mentioned my
long-suffering wife,
Pat. She has supported me and all my
endeavors, no matter how weird they may
have been over the years, for our 61
years of married life. Thank you.
I'd also like to thank David Flesher for
his remarks earlier tonight. That was
really a total surprise to me. David has
done a fabulous job at Case Western
Reserve as the associate provost in
charge of international affairs. when he
came there which I think was about six
or seven years ago the percentage of
undergraduates case uh who were foreign
students was about 2 and 12% and now
it's 13% and much of that is
attributable to David's
work when they heard about this someone
asked me well what is it that justifies
you to be part of the international hall
of fame
And I had to think a little bit about
that. I came up with six experiences
that may relate to this wonderful honor.
Number one, when I was 2 years old, I
spent a year in
Paris. And my father was a young
associate at a New York Boston law firm
and they wanted to open an office in
Paris and they wanted the youngest
associate in the firm to go along with a
partner and so he went of course I went
with it and I'm told that after that
year on the boat coming back to the US
my language was such a hodgepodge of
French and English nobody could
understand me except my
parents. So that was sort of my first
experience with the international field.
Number two, when I graduated from
college in
1950, I took a sleeping bag and three of
my classmates and we spent a year
hitchhiking around Europe. We could do
it in those days. And uh it was a
amazing experience in a way because each
of us spent for the whole summer about
$1,000 each. You can do it in those
days. Well, while I was there, I fell in
love with this beautiful Italian girl. I
met her on a train from Madrid to
Venice. She spoke not a word of English.
I spoke about a word of d but somehow we
were able to communicate and it was a
wonderful experience.
Number three, in the 1970s, I through
some peculiar circumstances, I became
the US lawyer for Redum Limited, which
in those days was the world's largest
producer of roof tiles, which are used
throughout Europe and uh I was their US
lawyer and ultimately I became a member
of the parent board in
Vgate and for about 12 years I made a
trip could write a through London every
other month. And so during that time, I
came to learn and love London. It was a
wonderful city. I still think it's just
about the finest city in the world, next
to Cleveland, of
course. Number four, in
1972, I was working at the board of
directors of a local company here called
Rok Incorporated out in Aurora. They
make large earrings from 24 in to 30 ft
in diameter. And they were eventually
acquired by a very large German steel
company. And so these Germans love to
travel. And so our port with the Germans
dominating the port traveled to exotic
places like
Botenb the island of Madiraa in the
middle of the Atlantic Ocean and New
York, New
Jersey.
Number five. In
1991, I was chairman of the Greater
Cleveland Growth Association. And as
someone that's mentioned this evening,
uh we got the idea that in those days
that we should quote internationalize
Cleveland, Cleveland had been referred
to by a lot of the media as another
Ruskel city. And uh we didn't think that
was fair or appropriate. And so we set
out
to change that image. And it was really
amazing that Mayor Mike White had
virtually the same idea at the exact
same time we did. So we pulled our
resources, excuse me. And we formed the
organization called the International
Trade Alliance. And it had three
objectives. One, expand exports from
Cleveland abroad. two, try to attract
more reverse investment of foreign firms
into the Cleveland area. And three,
internationalize cause our people here
to think of themselves as living and
being in an international city. We had
this sort of defeist mentality that we
were just a Midwestern city with bus and
we didn't think that was a fair
characterization. So those were our
three objectives and I think the trade
alliance did some very good things for
about a decade. Eventually financial
pressures and other things caused it to
to basically morph into what is now
global payment but I was very glad to
have that experience. And some of the
arguments that we used were
that the uh we were an oceangoing port
by reason of the same seaway. We had at
that time it's probably about the same
over
117 nationality groups that were active
and busy here. You've heard about some
of them tonight. And in addition in
those days, Continental Airlines had
non-stop service to London. So all of
those factors we promote to try to
international high school and number six
and most important and some was referred
to
this when I became a man's day in
1984 the legal profession was expanding
and growing rapidly and we could see
that if we had continued to have a
leading position in the profession would
have to become part of the international
legal
practice. We spent a lot of time trying
to figure out how to do that. It wasn't
easy, but uh we we uh I spent a good
part of my time for six or seven years
roaming around Europe and Asia trying to
find good opportunities. And during that
period, we were able to open offices in
Paris
and Brussels, Riad, Geneva, Hong Kong,
Tokyo. So it was a it was an exciting
time and a lot of wonderful experiences
and uh it was it was somewhat scary
because you know this was a big
investment could have come crashing down
and as long as you said our partners
weren't exactly ecstatic about getting
but ultimately it paid off. So those are
my claims to international
relationship. But uh I really am just
totally overwhelmed by this honor. And I
I highly salute and congratulate the
Cleveland International Hall of Fame for
continuing to promote Cleveland as a
truly international city. All of here
deserve that recognition. Thank you very
much.